我自伤
? I hurt myself today
以感受
? To see if I still feel
凝神于疼痛
? I focus on the pain
疼痛是唯一的真实
? The only thing that's real
针尖蜇噬伤口
? The needle tears a hole
刺痛一如往日
? The old familiar sting
只想湮灭记忆
? Try to kill it all away
往事却并不如烟
? But I remember everything
我已然如此
? What have I become
我的挚爱
? My sweetest friend
至交旧友
? Everyone I know
皆已随风化去
? Goes away in the end
唯你超越一切
? And you could have it all
超越尘世
? My empire of dirt
唯恐负你
? I will let you down
唯恐伤你
? I will make you hurt
愿负荆棘之冠
? I wear this crown of thorns
献于谎者之位
? Upon my liar's chair
记忆片片而碎
? Full of broken thoughts
碎不可补
? I cannot repair
时光流转
? Beneath the stains of time
万念成空
? The feelings disappear
你已非你
? You are someone else
我仍空守
? I am still right here
我已然如此
? What have I become
我的挚爱
? My sweetest friend
至交旧友
? Everyone I know
皆已随风化去
? Goes away in the end
唯你超越一切
? And you could have it all
超越尘世
? My empire of dirt
唯恐负你
? I will let you down
唯恐伤你
? I will make you hurt
若能从头再来
? If I could start again
愿踏万水千山
? A million miles away
矢志不渝
? I would keep myself
上下求索
? I would find a way
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿好  somehacker  卫老哥  茶炒栗子
■
翻译：惠子  幸田实果子  Eowyn  敏基
时间轴：阿包  凭陵新月  Sagelibra
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   精校&总监： 阿好
我知道这种方式
I read that it works this way--
治疗师静静等着
that the therapist waits
让沉默一直蔓延
until the silence becomes so unbearable
迫使病人开口
that the patient is forced to speak.
你想采用哪种方式都行  冉先生
It can work any way you want, Mr. Wren.
你有什么特别想谈的吗
Is there something particular you'd like to talk about?
丧恸  我想谈谈丧恸
Grief. I'd like to talk about grief.
当然
Of course.
如果丧恸有最终目标  我想了解
I wanna know how it works, if it has a purpose.
这是个很大的问题
That's a big question.
也许我们应该谈谈
It might be best if we talk about
你的特定情况
your specific circumstances.
你失去了什么人吗
Have you lost someone?
我的挚友  发生了意外
My closest friend. There was an accident.
我当时跟他在一起
I was with him.
我很遗憾  冉先生
I'm very sorry, Mr. Wren.
现在有人能安慰你吗
Do you have someone to comfort you during this time?
我有过伴侣  但现在结束了
I was in a relationship, but that's over now.
这种精神创伤
The emotional fallout from these types of traumas
往往影响深远
can be extensive.
回到你刚才的问题  丧恸
Which brings us to your question--grief.
是否有个最终目标
Whether it has a purpose.
演变而出的目标
An...evolutionary purpose.
我是说
I mean,
我发现自己在重新评估自己之前的选择
I find myself reevaluating choices that I've made,
有些事  我本该换种方式处理
things that... I should have done differently
处理得更好
or better.
仿佛失去一切后  我才终于明白
As if in losing everything, I finally understand.
但我忽然想到
But then it occurs to me that--
你忽然想到
It occurs to you
这种感觉也许是暂时的
that this feeling might be temporary.
人在经历丧恸时  常常会有这种虚妄的意识
There's a false sense of lucidity that often accompanies grieving.
我在考虑采取点激进的行为
I've been thinking about doing something radical
以纪念他
as a tribute to his memory.
我对此并不支持  冉先生
I would caution against that, Mr. Wren.
我见过很多类似情况
I see this so often.
我接触过很多
I've been working with
今年港口爆炸案的幸存者
the survivors of the ferry bombing earlier this year.
他们的创伤和你类似
Their trauma is similar to yours.
当然也有更严重的
More extreme, of course.
很多人感觉自己对此负有责任
Many of them experience a sense of responsibility for what happened.
"幸存者内疚"  我知道
Survivor's guilt. I'm familiar.
那你肯定也知道我下面要说的话
Then you're also familiar with what I'm about to say next--
你认为朋友之死是你的错
that you think your friend's death was your fault.
否则  你就要面对痛苦的现实
Otherwise, you'd have to face a very painful truth.
什么现实
Which is what?
你不是上帝
That you are not God.
你掌控不了生死
You don't control who lives or dies.
这种无能为力同时也意味着
That powerlessness also means
朋友之死不是你的错
that your friend's death is not your fault.
我保证  冉先生
I assure you, Mr. Wren,
假以时日  你的内疚感
in time, the guilt you feel
会过去的
will pass.
那我问问你
Let me ask you a question then.
如果发生的一切真的是自己的错
Does survivor's guilt pass when everything that has happened
那"幸存者内疚"还会过去吗
actually is, in fact, your fault?
你看起来疲惫不堪  哈罗德
You look tired, Harold.
跟我说说话
Please talk to me.
我无话可说  格罗夫斯女士
I have nothing to say, Ms. Groves.
我之前就提议过
I offered before.
让我帮你
Let me help you.
已经晚了
It's a little too late for that,
不是吗
don't you think?
救约翰还不晚
Not for John.
他有麻烦了  我从你的表情中能看出来
He's in trouble. I can tell by the look on your face.
我不想表现得冷酷无情  哈罗德
And I don't want to sound unsympathetic, Harold,
但我们现在有更大的麻烦
but we have much bigger problems at hand.
你的机器安排我应对的事情
Whatever your machine was trying to prepare me for...
就快发生了
it's coming.
什么事  警探
Yes, detective?
有大麻烦了
We got a big problem.
对讲机里听到的
I heard the call on the radio.
有人横撞了过来  还在车子着火时审问他
Someone t-boned him then interrogated him while the car burned.
前排的有可能活下来
Guys in the front might make it.
后排已经烧糊了
Guy in the back may make a good bag of charcoal.
有目击者在现场看到了咱那位精神错乱的义警
Witnesses put our pal, the psychopathic vigilante,
哪一位
Which one?
这意思是说你那俩流浪犬都跑出去了
You mean both your stray dogs are off the leash?
这是那位高酷疯的杰作
This was the handiwork of tall, dark, and deranged.
我都不敢去想另一个在干嘛了
And I shudder to think what the other one's up to.
我相信他们中至少有一位
I have reason to believe that one or both of them
想要追杀西蒙斯
are looking to track down and kill Simmons.
我们都想杀西蒙斯
We all want Simmons.
王八蛋杀了我搭档  还追杀我儿子
Piece of crap killed my partner, then went after my kid.
但这种大杀八方的焦土手段
But the scorched earth campaign is only gonna make
只会让西蒙斯更难找
Simmons harder to find, not easier.
他们是谁
Who were they?
高级人渣
Dirtbags of the highest order.
贩卖毒品  经营童妓
Run drugs, underage hookers.
还有假文件
And a lot of paper.
-假文件  -对  假证件
- Paper? - Yeah, counterfeit bills.
身份证  护照  上边的名字是约克
I.D.s, passports, for a forged name Yorke.
那我们得赶紧找到约克先生
We'd better find Mr. Yorke then.
定位主体
约克  西蒙
皇后区
放我下来
Get me down.
拜托
Come on.
3条语音信息
未知发信人
放我下来  贱人
Take me down, you bitch!
我知道的都告诉你了
I told you everything I know.
可我就是不相信你
And somehow, I just don't believe you.
伙计  快报警
Guys, call the cops!
你想试试吗
You wanna take a crack at him?
我打到手都疼了
My gun hand's cramping.
他看起来不太好
Guy's not looking so good.
-你打断他的腿了  -没  里瑟干的
- Did you break his legs? - Nope. Reese did.
他先找到人
Got to him before I did.
把他从楼上扔了下来
Dropped him off the roof of the building.
他在停车场嚎救命时被我发现了
I found his sorry ass in the parking lot yelling for help.
不过还有胳膊在
Still got his arms, though.
你看到里瑟了吗
Did you see Reese?
我到的时候已经走了
Gone by the time I got here.
-我们得阻止他  -何必呢
- We have to stop him. - Why?
少一个杀害警察的黑警我觉得挺好
One less dirty cop-killing cop sounds good to me.
且不说你的
Setting aside your somewhat...
二元道德标准  肖女士
binary moral compass, Ms. Shaw,
你要知道里瑟先生的伤势危及生命
You should know that Mr. Reese's injuries are life-threatening.
好吧  哈罗德
All right, Harold.
我们照你的法子来
We'll play it your way.
但如果里瑟不想被人找到
But if Reese doesn't wanna be found,
那我们找他的唯一法子就是找到西蒙斯
our only way of tracking him is by finding Simmons ourselves.
这家伙交待了吗
Guy give you anything?
说
Speak up!
唯一一个知道
The only one who knows
西蒙斯逃跑计划的人是他老大  奎恩
Simmons' exit strategy is his boss, Quinn.
如果你们要找他  那就排队吧
And if you're looking for him, get in line.
所有人都想要他死
Everybody wants him dead.
我现在能去医院了吗  拜托了
Can I go to the hospital now, please?
你在联调局有门路没
You got an inside track to the Feds?
我们得在里瑟之前找到奎恩
We gotta get to Quinn before Reese does.
你开玩笑吗  奎恩手下大堆黑警
Are you kidding? Quinn ran a bunch of corrupt cops.
联调局才不会理我
Feds aren't talking to me.
我知道有一个人会知道奎恩在哪里
I know one man who will know Quinn's location.
被捕之后  奎恩聘请了吉米・拉森尼
After his arrest, Quinn retained Jimmy Ransone--
臭名昭著的高价刑事辩护律师
high-dollar criminal defense attorney with a questionable reputation.
被保护性羁押的嫌疑人也有权见律师
But even suspects in protection are allowed to see their lawyer.
等等  别这样  伙计们
Wait a minute, come on, guys!
放我下来
Get me down!
别这样  放我离开这儿
Come on, get me the hell outta here!
我看咱家男孩儿来了又走了
I'd say our boy's come and gone.
芬奇
Finch?
我们有个麻烦
We got a problem.
你们没找到拉森尼先生吗
You couldn't find Mr. Ransone?
我们找到了他的遗体
We found what's left of him.
有人把他当烟灰缸用过
Someone used him as an ashtray
然后一枪打穿了他的脑子
before putting a bullet through his head.
里瑟这回是真来狠的了
Reese has really gone off the reservation this time.
不  里瑟根本不抽烟
No. Reese doesn't even smoke.
他最多用个打火机
He would have just used a lighter.
这个太夸张做作  业余
This...is theatrical. Amateur hour.
至少知道了他还活着
At least we know he's still alive.
他伤势如何  肖女士
How badly is he injured, Ms. Shaw?
看上去不好  我们时间不多了
He doesn't look so good. We don't have much time.
里瑟走了  五分钟后  这些小丑出现了
Reese leaves, and five minutes later, these jokers show up.
俄罗斯人
Russians.
应该是
It figures.
奎恩做了污点证人指证他们
Quinn turned state evidence against them.
现在里瑟先生和俄罗斯人
So now both Mr. Reese and the Russians
都知道去哪儿找阿伦佐・奎恩
know where to find Alonzo Quinn,
而我们依然不知道
and we still don't.
拉森尼是唯一一个能告诉我们里瑟去向的人
Ransone is the only one that can tell us where Reese is going.
不是唯一一个
Not the only one.
还有谁
Who?
哈罗德知道我在说谁
Harold knows who I'm talking about.
我们别无选择了
We're running out of options.
我们需要根
We need Root.
我们得讨论一下洛夫廷的病例
We need to discuss the Loftin case.
白人男性  83岁  罹患急性肺炎
Caucasian male, 83, presented with acute pneumonia.
我知道病例  肖医生
I know the case, Dr. Shaw.
我也知道你与洛夫廷家人的沟通
I also know about your interaction with the Loftin family.
你走进等候室
You walked into the waiting room
吃着根能量棒
eating an energy bar
告诉洛夫廷的家人
and proceeded to tell the Loftin family
他们的父亲死了
that their father was dead.
因为他是死了
Because he was.
想必你当时很饿吧
And, presumably, you were hungry.
你救活了洛夫廷先生四次
You managed to revive Mr. Loftin four times
你那么坚决果断地拯救他们的父亲
you went to truly heroic measures to save their father,
但是  洛夫廷全家将记住的
and yet, all the Loftin family will remember
是这医生一边告诉他们噩耗
is the doctor who gave them the worst possible news
一边吃着糖果棒
while she was eating a candy bar.
我来问问你
Let me ask you this:
你是否在乎病人的生死
do you care if your patients live or die?
当然
Of course.
但是那会触痛你吗
But does it hurt you?
我观察你有  一段时间了
I've been watching you for...some time,
你似乎不为所动
and it doesn't seem to bother you.
这里的医生
This place is filled with doctors
全都不在乎病人生死
who don't care if their patients live or die.
不  这里的医生
No, this place is filled with doctors
全都假装不在乎
who pretend they don't care.
但是你不一样  是吧
But you're different, aren't you?
医生们对你的评价都一样
Your attendings all say the same thing about you--
技术一流
technically brilliant,
无比冷静
remarkably calm.
他们看不透你的本质
They can't spot what you really are.
什么本质
And what's that?
你对《精神疾病诊断手册》倒背如流  医生
You know the DSM backwards and forwards, doctor.
你可能第一年就自我诊断过了
You probably diagnosed yourself in your first year.
诊断出了
A diagnosis which meant that
这专业一开始就不该接受你
you never should have been accepted into this program.
我看着其他人
I watch the others.
我看着恐惧占据他们的内心
I watch the fear creep into them.
我看着他们屡屡犯错
I watch them make mistakes,
你认为我所缺失的那些情感
and you think these feelings that I'm lacking
会让他们更出色吗
make them better?
换成你真的宁愿是他们给你治病
You'd really rather have one of them working on you
而不是我吗
instead of me?
是的  因为
Yes. Because if...
如果当你的病人最需要你的时候
if the only thing motivating you is technical mastery,
你的唯一动力却是在技术上精益求精
when one of your patients needs you the most,
那么  这工作会让你感觉无聊
then...this job just might start to bore you.
这就是"修修补补"和"救死扶伤"的区别
That's the difference between fixing and healing.
你非常聪明  萨姆恩
You have a brilliant mind, Sameen.
而且你很有天赋
And you're very gifted.
但你永远当不了医生
But you'll never be a doctor.
没时间了  哈罗德
Time's up, Harold.
这不是我们可以轻易决定的事
This is not something we should go about lightly.
这是唯一的法子
It's the only way.
这一决定将会导致严重的后果
There will be larger consequences if we make this decision,
我们得做好准备
we need to be ready for that.
以约翰目前的身体状态  如果陷入
John isn't gonna make it if he winds up in a crossfire
联调局和黑帮的交火中  他撑不下来
between a bunch of Feds and organized criminals in his current state.
我知道这是我们唯一的选择  肖女士
I know this is our only option, Ms. Shaw.
我只是希望我们为即将发生的事做好准备
I just wanna make sure we're prepared for what may happen.
我做好了
I'm in.
你呢
Are you?
我猜这不是给我的
I'm guessing that isn't for me.
你们要早告诉我这种拼车安排
You know, if you told me about the carpooling arrangements,
我就自己开车来了
I would have driven separately.
格罗夫斯女士是来帮我们找阿伦佐・奎恩的
Ms. Groves is here to help us locate Alonzo Quinn.
就要到了  关掉车灯
We're close. Turn off the headlights.
那我怎么看路
How am I supposed to see?
你不需要
You don't need to.
匀速前进250米
Steady for another 800 feet.
感觉到之后左转
Adjust left when you feel it.
感觉到什么
Feel what?
哈罗德  下车的时候拿着急救箱  好吗
Harold, grab the first aid kit when we get out of the car, will you?
停到右边
Pull over to the right.
我们干嘛要听这个绑架过眼镜儿的疯女人的话
Tell me why we're listening to the crazy chick who kidnapped glasses.
你右边的口袋里有85美分
In your right pocket, you have 85 cents.
早上买咖啡找回的零钱
The change from your morning coffee run.
你公寓里  有一张你爸爸小时候
In your apartment, there's an old photo of your father
在富兰克林公园动物园拍的照片
at the Franklin Park Zoo taken when he was a child.
他在喂一只幼狮
He's feeding a lion cub.
你知道那只幼狮的名字吗
Do you know what that cub's name was?
莱奈尔
Lionel.
这就是你名字的由来
That's where your name came from.
我保证
I promise...
我是来帮忙的
I'm here to help.
每次我以为跟你们混的日子已经怪得登峰造极时
Just when I think life with you people couldn't get any weirder,
你们总有人能再创新高
one of you takes it to the next level.
我们在哪儿  格罗夫斯女士
Where are we, Ms. Groves?
我现在能要把枪吗
May I have a gun now?
你的听力出什么毛病了
What's with you and your poor listening skills?
没  门
No...way.
那你最好转身
Then you better turn around.
跟我来
Follow me.
把他也带上
And bring him with you.
你刚开枪打了名联邦法警
You just shot a federal marshal.
一般人我不告诉他  不是第一次了
Just between us... not my first time.
等十二点钟方向的灯亮起来
Wait for the light at 12:00.
那是
Is that...
阿伦佐・奎恩
Alonzo Quinn.
那栋大楼有两个主要出口
The building has two main exits,
两个应急出口
two emergency exits.
有十二个联邦法警看守
12 U.S. Marshals guard the building,
我们那位朋友
Plus our friend over there
刚才已经检查过了我们现在这里
who was scouting the perimeter that we're now inside.
空中支援只需十分钟便到
Air support is ten minutes out.
俄罗斯人还没到
While the Russians aren't here yet,
但也快了
they will be soon.
你确定大个子在这儿
You sure the big guy's here?
-这是怎么回事  -快来
- What the hell was that? - Move in!
非常确定
Pretty sure.
你的测试分数很高  但我还有所怀疑
Your test scores are good, but I have my doubts about you.
我认为你太软弱
You look soft to me.
长官  不  不  长官
Sir, no. No, sir.
瞧  我说的就是这个
See, that's what I'm talking about.
开口闭口"长官"
Stop with the "Sirs."
你全身上下  彻头彻尾就是只菜鸟
You're green from the soles of your feet to the top of your pointy head.
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
你是不是还期待我问问你的感受
Were you expecting me to ask about your feelings?
因为你将要体验生死一线的生活
'Cause you're about to join men living out on the ragged edge
要使用极端手段
where extreme actions are required
阻止极端坏事发生
to stop extremely bad things from happening.
你准备好行使恐怖手段
Are you prepared to do terrible things
并在必要时抛之脑后吗
and then turn it off when you need to?
是的  长官  我准备好了
Yes, sir. I am.
你能否下手杀死一名有幼子在旁的恐怖分子
Could you kill a terrorist standing 2 feet from his young son?
直接爆头  转身离开
Blow his head off and then walk away
任凭孩子在爸爸的尸体旁边痛哭
while the kid cries next to his daddy's dead body?
只要一声令下  长官
If those are my orders, sir.
这儿写着  你爸在你小时候就过世了
Says here your dad died when you were just a kid.
也是军人
Army man too.
你会不会不合时宜地认为
You're not gonna decide at the wrong time
孩子需要父亲
that a child should have a father,
即便他父亲是恐怖分子
even if that father is a terrorist?
不  长官
No, sir.
很抱歉这么对你  孩子
I'm sorry for going at you like this, son,
但我是你驶向黑暗前的最后一站了
but I'm the last stop between you and the darkness that awaits you.
我得确定  你的精神强大到足以加入此项目
I need to be sure that you're mentally tough enough for this program.
如果你搞砸了  害你的兄弟们被杀
If you spun out, got your brothers killed,
责任在我
it would be on me.
这是你的工作
You're just doing your job.
我理解
I get it.
我以前经历过一次了
I've been through this before.
没人能经历第二次
No one does this twice.
如果你被淘汰
If you washed out,
我们不会再次招募你
we wouldn't have recruited you again.
我没被淘汰
I didn't wash out.
我加入这项目三年了
I've been a part of this program for three years.
备受信赖
A very trusted part.
事实上  我的指挥官派我去查明
In fact, my C.O. tasked me with finding out
是谁把我们特工的名单
who's been selling the names of our operatives
卖给中国反情报机构
to Chinese counterintelligence.
费了点时间  但我查出来了
Took me a while, but I found him.
你应该乖乖只做你的工作
If only you'd just done your job.
你做得还挺不错
You're pretty damn good at it.
谁来赔偿损失
Who the hell pays for the damage?
快回去
Get back inside now.
我要通知波拉克  我们需要空中支援
I'm radioing Pollack. We need air support.
进去  进去
Get in. Get in.
长官  你看见了吗
Sir, are you seeing this?
我们是否需要请求空中支援
Do we need to call for air support?
只是皇后区有车辆起火
It's a car fire in Queens.
这事没必要请求空中支援
I'm not calling air support for that.
快速反应队在二楼待命
Rapid Response Team standing by on the second floor.
让你的人进行周边检查  汇报情况
Have your men do a perimeter check and report back.
收到
Copy that.
俄罗斯的  联调局的  我不管
Russians, Feds-- I don't care.
我只想知道  谁来赔偿
I just want to know who pays for the...
损失
damage?
你应该请求支援
You should probably call for backup.
你担心你的旧部下
You worried some of your old buddies
会跑过来闲扯吗
came to shoot the breeze?
遗憾的是  我的手下非常强干
Sadly, my men are very good at their jobs.
任何人想碰你  他们得要有完全的
Anybody wants a crack at you, they're gonna need an entire--
长官  长官  有个状况
Sir. Sir, we've got a situation.
罗宾斯倒下
Robbins is down,
酒店的门从里面反锁了
and the hotel doors have been secured from the inside.
有人进去了
Someone's in there with you.
守住门  快
Secure the door. Now.
待命小组  我是亮区
Ready team, this is Highlight.
分头到楼梯井
Spread out to the stairwell.
别放任何人上三楼  可能有多名狙击手
No one gets to three. Expect multiple shooters.
收到  全面封锁
Copy that. We'll lock down.
守住走廊
Secure the hallways.
我们要把犯人带出去  快
We're taking the prisoner out now.
看来我低估了你的人气
Looks like I underestimated your popularity.
我们走
Let's move.
无济于事
No point.
追杀我的那个人
The guy who's coming after me...
你的手下挡不住他
your men won't be able to stop him.
等等
Wait a second.
听我命令  上  上
On my mark-- Go! Go!
汇报情况  汇报情况
Report! Report!
发现三名狙击手  也许四名
I made three shooters, maybe four.
听我指令
On my count--
三  二
three, two...
抱歉
Sorry...
但我得向你保护的这人要句话
but I need a word with the man you're protecting.
你刚才袭击了十几名法警
You just attacked a dozen marshals.
抱歉也没用
Sorry's not gonna cut it.
他们只需要点阿司匹林
They'll need some Aspirin,
也许再加点理疗  走
maybe a little physical therapy -- move.
你就休息下吧
You sit this one out.
西蒙斯
Simmons...
我要他的逃跑计划
I want his exit.
忠诚
Loyalty.
这是西蒙斯追杀你和卡特的原因
That's why Simmons came after you and Carter.
忠诚
Loyalty.
这是我们组建整个组织的基础
That's how we built this whole damn thing.
如果我的回报是背弃忠诚  会遭天谴
I'll be damned if I repay that loyalty by breaking it now.
即使你威胁杀了我
Even if you threaten to kill me.
知道吗
You see?
这是你我互相理解的原因
That's why you and I understand each other.
你做的每件事都叫人恶心
Now, everything you do is an abomination.
但你说出的话
But your word...
你说出的话就是你的承诺
your word is your bond.
对你的教子
To your godson.
对卡特
To Carter.
你言出必行
You do what you say.
我也是
So do I.
我不会威胁杀了你
I'm not gonna threaten to kill you.
我会杀了你
I'm going to kill you...
无论你说不说
whether you tell me or not.
没得商量
No bargaining.
三分钟后
In three minutes...
你死
you're dead.
我杀过很多人
I've killed many people.
从不多受困扰
Never bothered me much.
这是我精于此道的原因
That's why I was good at it.
但我不喜欢让他们太痛苦
I didn't like them suffering, though.
我花费数年才练出快速无痛的解决方式
Took me years to figure out how to do it quickly, painlessly.
但如果你不说
But if you don't tell me,
我会把那些方式抛之脑后  明白吗
I'm gonna forget all of that. Understand?
我会让你人生的最后的三分钟
And I'll make the last three minutes of your life
永无止境
last forever.
现在能麻烦给我把枪吗
Can I please have a gun now?
不行  你问得快要激怒我了
No, and you're really starting to irritate me by asking.
根如此索要武器  肖女士
As far as Root's request for a weapon, Ms. Shaw,
形势怕是要愈发凶险了
the situation is becoming increasingly dangerous.
是啊  真不扯蛋
Yeah, no kidding!
她要是想杀我们
And if she wanted to kill us,
我猜我们已经死过很多回了
I'm guessing she could have done so many times already.
别捎上我们  哈罗德
Speak for yourself, Harold.
好吧  无所谓了  拿上
But fine. Whatever. Take it.
我能再要一把吗
Can I have a second one, please?
还要双枪  逊
Two guns at once? That's kinda lame.
行了吧  走吧
You all set? Let's head up.
太迟了
Too late.
她去哪儿
Where's she going?
好吧  挺辣的
Okay, that was kinda hot.
我看着前门
I'll watch the front.
你们快去  我们快没时间了
You should head up. We're almost out of time.
时间到
Time's up.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
你知道乔丝牺牲了什么
You know what Joss sacrificed
来以她的方式扳倒这个男人
to bring this man down on her terms.
法律的方式
Legal terms.
一切
Everything.
是的
Yes.
所以如果你杀了奎恩先生
So if you're going to kill Mr. Quinn,
别以为是以她的名义
don't imagine that you're doing it in her name.
她不想那样
That's not what she would have wanted.
我们应该一开始就杀了他
We should have killed him in the first place.
为什么没杀呢  芬奇
Why didn't we, Finch?
那不是我们的目标
That's not our purpose.
我们拯救生命  你拯救生命
We save lives. You save lives.
并非所有人的生命
Not all of them.
你快不行了  约翰
You're dying, John.
让我们帮你
Let us help you.
不
No.
带他离开这里
Let's get him outta here.
我留下  确保联调局
I'll stay and make sure the Feds
重新关押这个混蛋
take this piece of garbage back into custody.
我们该去追西蒙斯
We should be going after Simmons.
里瑟找到了他的位置
Reese got his location.
有时人必须做出抉择  肖女士
Sometimes you have to make choices, Ms. Shaw.
我们已经失去了一个朋友
We've already lost a friend.
我今晚不想再失去一个
I don't intend to lose another-- not tonight.
真不敢相信我们就这么让他跑了
I just can't believe we're gonna let him get away.
机器可从没说过里瑟是唯一
The machine never said Reese was the only one
计划杀西蒙斯的
planning to kill Simmons.
我们谈了快二十分钟了  莱奈尔
We've been talking for nearly 20 minutes, Lionel,
可你几乎什么都没说
but you've said almost nothing.
我还觉得咱俩聊得挺投机
And I thought we were really starting to hit it off.
这里很安全
Look, this is a safe place.
虽然市政府付我工资
I may get paid by the city,
但我为每一名走进我办公室的警员服务
but I serve the police officers who come into my office.
是吗
Yeah?
那就给我来杯波本威士忌加冰吧
In that case, I'll take a Bourbon on rocks.
酗酒是经历枪战后的警员的常见问题
Alcohol abuse is common among officers after a shooting.
讽刺也是
So is sarcasm.
事发之后  你睡眠如何
How have you been sleeping since the incident?
还行
Just fine.
你被迫终止了一个人的生命
You were forced to take someone's life.
这不容易
That's a hard pill to swallow,
即便开枪是正当行为
even when the shooting was justified.
好吧
Fine.
我遭遇了嫌犯
I encountered the suspect--
最好说出他的名字
It's better if you use his name.
好吧  我碰见了朱尔斯
Okay. I encountered Jules.
当时很黑  他看见了我  想拔枪
It was dark, he saw me, went for his piece.
我动作更快  结束
I got to mine first. The end.
那经历一定很恐怖
That must have been terrifying.
你有可能被杀
You could have been killed.
我的工作啊
Part of the job.
那么  我的工作
Yeah, well, part of my job,
莱奈尔  是帮助一些警察
Lionel, is dealing with cops
他们看似坚强  最后却饮弹自尽
who act tough and end up eating a bullet
原因便是未经治疗的创伤后遗症
because of a cascade of untreated posttraumatic symptoms.
你可以在别人面前隐藏你的真实感受
Now, you can hide your real feelings from everyone else,
但面对我  你必须真实
but with me, you need to get real.
好吧
All right.
这里很安全  是吧
This is a safe place, right?
医患保密协议之类的  是吧
Doctor-patient, confidential, all that, right?
对  你在这里所说的一切都受到保护
Yes, everything you say here is completely protected.
利用这段时间卸下重担吧
Use this time to unburden yourself.
那枪开得不对
Wasn't a good shooting.
我相信你可能会有这种感觉  不过
I'm sure you may feel that way, but--
那根本不是什么感觉
Ain't got anything to do with feelings.
朱尔斯去年打死一名下了班的菜鸟警察
You see, Jules shot an off-duty rookie last year.
才24岁
24 years old.
那孩子当时快当爹了
Kid had a baby on the way.
但好毒贩总是请得起好律师
But good drug dealers can afford good lawyers,
所以朱尔斯逍遥法外了
so Jules walked.
我跟踪了他好几个星期
I had been tracking him for weeks,
就等他落单
just waiting to get the guy alone.
那天就是了
And there he was,
他从杂货店里出来
walking out of a bodega,
志得意满
with not a care in the world.
毫无防备
No protection either.
他看见我了
He saw me.
他知道我为什么在那里
He knew why I was there.
我能从他眼里看出来
I could see it in his eyes.
所以我对他笑了
So I smiled at him.
然后把两颗子弹射进他的胸膛
Just before I put two in his chest.
你杀了人
You killed a man.
不
No.
他得到报应了
He got the devil's share.
什么
The...what?
朱尔斯这种人死了  这就叫报应
That's what you call it when a guy like Jules gets his.
天道循环  报应不爽
It's the way the world evens things out.
他罪有应得
Guy got what he deserved,
想知道我睡得如何吗
and you wanna know how I've been sleeping?
又香又甜
Like a baby.
不过还是谢谢你让我卸下重担
But thanks for letting me unburden myself.
错过飞机了
Missed your flight.
我告诉飞行员你赶不及了
I told the pilot you weren't gonna make it.
你打算怎么办  弗斯科
So what's the plan, Fusco?
开枪打个手无寸铁的人吗
Gonna shoot an unarmed man?
不
Nah.
我有个更好的主意
I got a better idea.
我忍了很久了
Been waiting to do this for a long time.
卡特赏你的一枪吧
Carter got you good, huh?
我知道  弗斯科
I get it, Fusco.
我一直知道你是个杀手
I always knew you were a killer.
快动手行吧
Get it over with, will ya?
就是这样
That's just it.
我本来会变得和你一样
I could've been just like you,
在底层自相残杀
a bottom-feeder who turns on his own kind.
为了什么  金钱  权力
For what? Money, power?
我很幸运
I got lucky.
有个搭档
I had a partner.
她对我很好
She was good for me.
方方面面
For a lot of reasons.
她让我知道我还能再做好人
She reminded me that I could be good again too.
我能做好父亲  好朋友
I could be a good father, a good friend.
好警察
A good cop.
我不会让你毁了她的成果
I'm not gonna let you undo all the good she did.
卡特救了我
Carter saved my life.
她  她拯救了误入歧途的我
She--she saved me from myself.
因为她相信我
Because she believed in me.
我不会为你这种人渣而毁了这一切
And I'm not gonna throw all that away on a piece of crap like you.
派崔克・西蒙斯  你被捕了
Patrick Simmons, you're under arrest.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent...
? There's a color in your hands
? Can never return, never get back, no
? There's a moment in your hands
医生说他能撑过去
Doctor said he's gonna pull through.
失血很多
Lost a lot of blood.
我会去曼哈顿综合医院再偷点
I'm gonna go steal some more from Manhattan General.
根呢
Where's Root?
? There's a color in your hands
? Can never erase, never rub out, no
看来他终于肯跟我亲近了
Think he's finally warming up to me.
你已经自由了
You were free.
为什么还要回来
Why did you come back?
我说过的
Like I said...
更大的战争即将到来
we have a larger fight ahead of us.
我想我们届时最好一起面对
I think we should be together when that begins.
你觉得呢
Don't you?
谢谢你
Thank you.
? There's a moment in your hands
? Never give up, never get slack, no
只有我  警官
It's just me, Officer.
以利亚
Elias.
你想干什么
What do you want?
奎恩和我都被抓了
Quinn and I are busted.
HR完了
HR is dead.
除了羞辱下我也没别的可做了
Nothing else to do but rub my face in it.
那不是我的风格
That's not really my style.
那你来这儿干什么
Then why the hell are you here?
有笔帐要清
There remains a debt.
文明的原则
Civilization rests on the principle
是我们对待罪犯
that we treat our criminals
要仁慈过他们对待受害者
better than they treated their victims,
我们不能降格到罪犯的水平
that we not stoop to their level.
但你我是异类
But you and I are outliers.
我们并不是文明的一部分
We're not really a part of civilization.
我们更加  原始
We're something...older.
当然也就是说
Which means, of course,
我们可以做些文明人不能做的事
that we can do the things that civilized people can't.
我多次提出替卡特警探除掉你
I offered to kill you for Detective Carter many times,
但她总是拒绝
and she always said no.
她直到终点仍坚守文明
She was civilized to the very end.
我想她不喜欢我
I don't think she liked me.
但我非常喜欢她
But I liked her very much,
你杀了她
and you killed her.
所以此刻我觉得有责任
So now I consider it my responsibility
来解决此一特殊问题
to fix the particular problem
就是你  西蒙斯警官
that is you, Officer Simmons.
你真觉得你会是最终杀掉我的人吗
You really think you're gonna be the one to kill me?
不不  我的朋友会杀掉你
No. No, my friend is going to kill you.
我只要看着
I'm just gonna watch.